A Finding Aid to the Millard Sheets Papers, 1907-1990, in the Archives of American Art AAA.sheemill
Archives of American Art
- Writings, 1936-1988, undated; Series 11; (boxes 20-22; 2.5 linear ft.)
  The files include drafts, notes, miscellaneous correspondence and background material. The series documents the significant time that Sheets devoted to expressing himself through literary forms. Sheets published articles for various magazines throughout his career. Of particular interest to researchers and scholars will be the articles by Sheets in 11.1 that describe his wartime experiences in India as a staff artist and war correspondent during World War II.
  This series is organized into three major subseries by type of material.
  11.1: Books and Articles, 1936-1988, undated
  11.2: Eulogies, 1965-1980, undated
  11.3: Lectures and Speeches, 1937-1980, undated
  - Books and Articles, 1936-1988, undated; 11.1
    This subseries includes drafts, notes, correspondence, and related background material that resulted in published articles or books by or about Millard Sheets. The folders authored by Sheets are arranged alphabetically by title of work. The folders authored by other about sheets are arranged alphabetically by name of the author.
    Within this subseries individual folders are arranged chronologically.
    - Books and Articles by Sheets (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Arthur Millier award text, 1973 (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - "An Artist Looks at the Music Center," Los Angeles Times, Sept. 30, 1964 (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - "The Attack on Bamboo Hill," Life, June 5, 1944 (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - "The Creative Process," The Rangefinder (see also 11.3, Drafts and Related Background Material, Aug. 20, 1967), circa 1968 (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - "The Designer in Industry," Interpace Technical Journal (see also Series 6, International Pipe & Ceramics Corp...., Correspondence, Whitmore, C.F., 1965-1966), Sept. 15, 1966 (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Foreword, unpublished manuscript by Janice Lovoos, circa 1965 (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Foreword, unpublished manuscript by Helen B. Dooley, 1965-1968 (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - "Lucien Labaudt," letters to the Editor, Life, Jan. 3, 1944 (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - "Mexico and the United States," undated (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - "Millard Sheets Writes From India,", circa 1944 (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - "On the Importance of Being A Good Person,", July 31, 1947 (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - "To Betty With Love," undated (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Transcript of Sheets's description of his wartime assignment in India and Burma, undated (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Your Drawing is a Measure of Your Mind, published by Millard Sheets, Gualala, Calif., 1983 (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Untitled, 1936 (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Untitled, undated (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Untitled article for Sunset Magazine, 1973 (Box 20, Reel 5703)
    - Books and Articles by Others (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Askew, Raul, "Mercantile Bank Sets New High in Blending Design with Work," Dallas Morning News, (Feb. 23, 1958) (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Berney, Charlotte, "Millard Sheets: Artist for the World," Antiques & Fine Arts, (Oct. 1987) (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Duggan, Shirle, "Artist Haven," Los Angeles Examiner, (Mar. 26, 1950) (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - King, Alma S., ed., "A One-Man Renaissance," Santa Fé East, (Winter 1987/Spring 1988) (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Lovoos, Janice and Edmund F. Penney, Millard Sheets: One-Man Renaissance, (1984), 1981 (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - MacMasters, Dan, "A Spurt of Creative Action in the Art of Ceramics," Los Angeles Times Home Magazine, (July 25, 1965) (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Magnan, George A., "Painting Watercolor with Millard Sheets," Today's Art, (Feb. 13, 1973), 1972-1973 (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Meyer, Susan E. and Norman Kent, Watercolorists at Work, (1973), 1970-1978 (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Millier, Arthur, "The Lindbergh of American Art," Los Angeles Times Sunday Magazine, (Mar. 6, 1938) (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - -------, Arthur, biographical sketch on Sheets, Famous Americans, second series, Charles Webb & Co., 1941 (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Nelson, Betty J., Sheets's Monumental Mosaics in California (master's thesis), San Jose University, (Dec. 1985) (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Paterno, Susan, "Muralist Brings Home Some Truths About Art," The Register, (Oct. 13, 1983) (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Richardson, A.T., untitled memoir, illustrated by Sheets, (1969?), 1969-1970 (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Ritchie, Ward, Nigger of the Narcissus, Limited Editions Book Club edition, (1965), 1962-1978, undated (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Ross, Kenneth, "Eloquent Dean of California Watercolorists," Los Angeles Times, (Apr. 11, 1976) (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Schluna, Vera, "Millard Sheets," Designers West, (Sept. 1966) (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Sheets, Mary Baskerville, A West African Journal, illustrated and published by Millard Sheets, Gualala, Calif., 1980-1981 (Box 20, Reel 5703)
      - Whitaker, Frederic, "Millard Sheets: Story of a Giant," American Artist, (Dec. 1964), 1964-1971 (Box 20, Reel 5703-5704)
      - -------, "Watercolor in California," American Artist, (May 1968), 1968-1969 (Box 20, Reel 5704)
  - Eulogies, 1965-1980, undated; 11.2
    This subseries consists of eulogies written by Sheets about personal friends and colleagues.
    The material is arranged alphabetically by name and then ordered chronologically within each folder.
    - Ames, Arthur, Apr. 26, 1975 (Box 20, Reel 5704)
    - Burgi, Kaspar, undated (Box 20, Reel 5704)
    - Childs, Kenneth D., Jr., Nov. 15, 1976 (Box 20, Reel 5704)
    - Dentzel, Carl, Nov. 9, 1980 (Box 20, Reel 5704)
    - Padelford, Louise, Sept. 8, 1979 (Box 20, Reel 5704)
    - Stewart, Albert, Sept. 23, 1965 (Box 20, Reel 5704)
  - Lectures and Speeches, 1937-1980, undated; 11.3
    This subseries consists of speeches and lectures written and delivered by Sheets before various public and private organizations.
    The files are grouped by type of material and then ordered chronologically within each folder.
    - Drafts and related background material, 1939-1956; (43 folders) (Box 20, Reel 5704)
    - Drafts and related background material, 1957-1972; (21 folders) (Box 21, Reel 5704-5705)
    - Drafts and related background material, 1973-1980, undated; (9 folders) (Box 22, Reel 5705)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1937-1980, undated; (5 folders) (Box 22, Reel 5706)
    - Television and radio appearances, 1953-1968, undated; (2 folders) (Box 22, Reel 5706)
- Printed Matter, 1936-1992, undated; Series 12; (boxes 22-25; 20 folders)
  This series include clippings, catalogs, brochures, magazines, and reprinted material collected by Sheets and his family.
  This series is arranged by alphabetically by subject and then ordered chronologically within each folder.
  - Capitol Mall Project, Redevelopment Agency of the City of Sacramento, 1963-1973, undated; (2 folders) (Box 22, Reel 5706)
  - Clippings, Art, 1969, 1981-1986, undated (Box 22, Reel 5706)
  - Clippings, California (unfilmed), 1975-1985 (Box 22, Reel 5706)
  - Clippings, Family activities, 1983-1984 (Box 22, Reel 5706)
  - Clippings, Horses (unfilmed; see also 3.1., 1939, 1978, undated), 1958-1963, undated (Box 22, Reel 5706)
  - Clippings, Jury publicity, 1941 (Box 22, Reel 5706)
  - Clippings, Maloof, Sam (unfilmed), 1985, undated (Box 22, Reel 5706)
  - Clippings, McNaughton, Elizabeth Baskerville (unfilmed; sister-in-law), 1958-1962, 1982, undated (Box 22, Reel 5706)
  - Clippings, Sheets, Millard (unfilmed; see also 9.1), 1936-1992, undated (Box 22, Reel 5706)
  - Clippings, Miscellaneous subjects (unfilmed), 1960-1985, undated (Box 22, Reel 5706)
  - Exhibition catalogs and announcements, 1956-1988, undated; (4 folders; unfilmed) (Box 22, Reel 5706)
  - Historical Foundation Center of America, Henderson, Nev., undated (unfilmed) (Box 23, Reel 5706)
  - Home Savings and Loan Association, Tiburon branch, Tiburon, Calif. (unfilmed), 1973-1976, undated (Box 23, Reel 5706)
  - Magazines featuring artwork by Sheets (unfilmed), 1944-1946, 1970-1987, undated (Box 23, Reel 5706)
  - Miscellaneous catalogs, flyers, and brochures, 1962-1981, undated; (unfilmed; 2 folders) (Box 23, Reel 5706)
  - Pomona, City of, Mall and Redevelopment Project, Pomona, Calif. (unfilmed; see also Series 6 and Series 13), 1959-1968, undated (Box 23, Reel 5706)
  - Reprints (unfilmed), 1965-1971 (Box 23, Reel 5706)
- Photographs, 1934-1983, undated; Series 13; (box 23; 16 folders)
  The files in this series predominantly reflect photo documentation of Sheets's artwork and design projects. Also found are photographs of his racing and breeding horses and personal publicity photographs.
  The series is arranged alphabetically by subject and then ordered chronologically within each folder.
  - Artwork, 1967, 1974, undated (Box 23, Reel 5706)
  - Horses (see also 3.1.), 1934-1975, undated (Box 23, Reel 5706)
  - International Pipe & Ceramics Corporation (Interpace), Los Angeles, Calif., 1958-1974, undated (Box 23, Reel 5707)
    - Los Feliz Plant, Los Feliz, Calif., 1963-1964 (Box 23, Reel 5707)
    - Miscellaneous photographs, 1965, undated (Box 23, Reel 5707)
    - Parsipanny office, Parsipanny, N.J., undated (Box 23, Reel 5707)
  - Japanese House, Los Angeles County Fair, Pomona, Calif., 1956 (Box 23, Reel 5707)
  - Miscellaneous subjects, undated (Box 23, Reel 5707)
  - National Shrine of the Immaculate Conception, Washington, D.C., 1967-1969, undated; (2 folders) (Box 23, Reel 5707)
  - Negatives (unfilmed), 1955-1965, undated (Box 23, Reel 5707)
  - Office building, Claremont, Calif., circa 1968 (Box 23, Reel 5707)
  - Pomona, City of, Mall and Redevelopment Project, Pomona, Calif., 1963-1964 (Box 23, Reel 5707)
  - San Jacinto Savings Association, Houston, Tex., circa 1966 (Box 23, Reel 5707)
  - Sheets, Millard, 1939, 1967-1983, undated (Box 23, Reel 5707)
  - Sutter Furniture Manufacturing Co., San Francisco, Calif., undated (Box 23, Reel 5707)
  - Van Dyver Witt Furniture Manufacturing Co., (Miller Desk), undated (Box 23, Reel 5707)
- Artwork, circa 1929, undated; Series 14; (box 23; 2 folders)
  This series consists mainly of original drawings created by Sheets's wife, Mary Baskerville Sheets, and a small group of sketches made by Sheets.
  The series is grouped alphabetically by artist and then ordered chronologically within each folder.
  - Sheets, Mary Baskerville, circa 1929, undated (Box 23, Reel 5707)
  - Sheets, Millard, undated (Box 23, Reel 5707)